Lucas Slade

Software Developer

(801) 608-3436



lucas.sheldon.slade@gmail.com in



LinkedIn/LucasSlade



GitHub/LucasSlade

Professional Software Developer and Army Veteran with 4+ years of military experience in cultivating teams, managing projects, and finding solutions to complex challenges. Utilizing communication skills with consistency to build rapport with thousands of consumers and businesses to provide products and services to contribute to growth and development of multiple companies.

Technical Skills

HTML - CSS - Bootstrap - JavaScript - jQuery - Java SE - Java EE (Servlets, JSP) - Spring - MySQL - Thymeleaf -Object-Oriented Programming - Test-Driven Development - Version Control with Git - Paired Programming

Development Projects

Nxt2Neighbor: https://github.com/Nxt2Neighbor-Capstone/Next2Neighbor

A full functioning application, providing a unique perspective in the real estate online shopping experience. Designed the front-end redirect capabilities, nav bar functionality and design, and page styling. Implemented the database using Spring Boot 6, with multiple relational tables. Helped configure backend functionality utilizing MVC.

Environment: JavaScript, CSS, BootStrap5, HTML, SpringBoot 6, Java, Thymeleaf, MySQL, JQuery

MR Weather Map: https://github.com/SladeLucas/codeup-web-exercises/blob/main/weather map.html

Mr Weather Map is an application that utilizes a weather API and map API simultaneously to provide an interactive weather searching experience. Designed the front-end capabilities. Utilized search and draggable functionality to allow users to interact with a global map, and receive weather data at any desired destination. Designed and implemented back-end capabilities to call and receive data from multiple APIs asynchronously

Environment: JavaScript, Bootstrap 5, HTML, CSS, JQuery

Cage Movie Reviews: https://github.com/Slade-Perez-Movies-Project/Slade-Perez-Movies-Project

Cage Movie Reviews is an interactive application that informs users of all Nicholas Cage's movies, and the reviews associated with each. Utilized JavaScript to allow users to input or delete movie reviews to the Json file associated with the application. Designed and implemented various tools from CSS and Bootstrap 5 to give life to the page with interactive animations, a loading screen, and dynamic responsiveness.

Environment: JavaScript, Bootstrap 5, HTML, CSS

Military Experience

Army - Fort Hood, TX

Receiving Manager / Nov 2020 - Nov 2022

- Handled housing and resource logistics to ensure the safe and efficient deployment of 50,000+ soldiers, as well as maintaining logistical supply documentation along with the security of the supply warehouse over two years of concurrent service
- Created schedules for and oversaw over 200 qualification tasks; managed a team of 30 soldiers
- Managed operations with the implementation of COVID protocols while maintaining the safety of 5000+ individuals during their mobilization process

Professional Experience

Peloton - Salt Lake City, UT Sales Lead / Jun 2019 - Jun 2020

- Generated \$500,000 in revenue sales in Peloton equipment
- Maintained the operation and security of \$50,000 worth of equipment on a daily basis
- Held over 2,000+ customer sales pitches with potential clients, 75% close rate

AT&T - Salt Lake City, UT

Sales Associate / Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

- Managed 200+ accounts on a daily, while managing sensitive customer information professionally
- Developed new sales pitches, and tactics which lead to the increase of total sales over 200%
- Maintained store security, when handling physical cash and balancing store registers

mVentix - Salt Lake City, UT

Territory Brand Ambassador / Dec 2016 - Jul 2018

- Looked after the overall sales performance of Vizio brand products for over 25 stores across the greater Salt Lake area
- Developed new professional relationships and trained over 200 employees throughout each store visited, held professional presentations for groups over 30 people on a monthly basis on upcoming technology
- Created schedules weekly and documented analytical data for all stores in the designated territory
- Trained daily on new products and the technology associated with new and upcoming Vizio brand products

Freelance - Los Angeles, CA

Musician and Songwriter / Jun 2014 - Jul 2021

- Conducted research and collaborated with other songwriters, musicians, and artists to produce quality lyrics and melodies
- Generating original ideas and playing around with traditional instruments like pianos, guitars, and drums to get a sense of how the piece might sound during a live performance
- Using software for editing, mixing, and mastering
- Pro Tools, LogicProX, Premier Pro, Photoshop, Lightroom

Education

Codeup

Certification of Completion

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 20-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development